The Amanda Seals Show.
Welcome back to The Amanda Seals Show.
It's Amanda Seals here,
and it is time for another edition of
I Be Knowing.
So the last few weeks have been one of self-reflection
and also outward reflection, by the way.
And I really am somebody who's always like asking myself,
like, could you have done that better?
Like, could you, you know,
could you have moved differently, et cetera?
And, you know, I don't think that every time
that you could have done something better
that you need to announce it every time.
I think there's also something to be said
for just doing it different the next time.
And I think it's really,
it's really a lot for a lot of people to do,
to just consider like,
okay, well, I learned the lesson.
And there's this false, to me,
there's this false sense of like,
everybody owes everybody all the time
because nobody even,
I just don't know a lot of people that even live by that,
but they love to tell everybody
what they're supposed to live by.
But what I wanted to say mainly though,
was that I feel like we live in a world,
particularly in a culture,
where when you are able to identify
what you find to be your strengths,
like your assets, et cetera,
there are so many times where people will tell you
that you are being haughty,
or you are being arrogant,
or you are being full of yourself
by you knowing yourself.
And so it means that oftentimes,
your validation has to come from outside.
But the thing about your validation coming from outside
is that we don't even have a community
that's set up to protect or support each other.
So if my validation is coming from a community
that's not even tasked or obligated to protect me,
then that just feels like a nonsensical way of existing.
This is how we end up creating narcissism too,
because you end up having to protect yourself.
And a lot of times people may have narcissistic behaviors,
even if they're not a comprehensive narcissist.
Everyone has narcissistic behaviors,
especially in a community that does not protect.
So in that regard,
when you say,
I will say,
I know that I'm a genius.
I know that.
Not just because of tests,
but I know that by my output.
I know that I am a creative powerhouse.
I know that I'm immensely talented,
but you're not allowed to say that,
particularly if you're a woman,
without people saying,
oh, you're too full of yourself.
But you know what?
I am full of myself.
And I'm so glad.
I would be much rather full of myself
than of what other people think of me.
Particularly when it's not people
that are necessarily even concerned with me.
That's a fact.
I think we need to be more full of ourselves
in that mindset,
in the set of being able to have your own self-confidence.
It's not delusional.
It doesn't mean you're selfish.
It doesn't mean you're discourteous.
It doesn't mean that you are unable
to see other perspectives.
But what it means is that
because you are full of yourself,
you are also demanding of yourself
to try your best,
to be your best self,
to analyze,
to self-reflect, etc.
And I feel like there's a lot of folks
who as long as everybody around them
is telling them that they're all right,
they don't feel the need to do that.
They're full of everyone else.
Okay.
I'm full of myself.
There you go.
I...